[This drama is fictional and any similarity with reality is purely coincidental.]
[이 드라마는 허구이며 어떠한 유사성도 있습니다. 현실은 순전히 우연이다.]
[Production guidelines were followed when filming children and animals.]
[생산 지침을 따랐습니다. 어린이나 동물을 촬영할 때.]
[Episode 4]
[4화]
Hello, everyone at Taehan Liquor.
안녕하세요 대한주류 여러분.
We have a company-wide announcement this week.
우리는 전사적으로 이번주 발표.
Manager Jang Hui Won from the New Product Development Team.
장희원 과장 신제품 개발팀에서.
Congratulations on your pregnancy.
임신을 축하드립니다.
That's impossible.
그것은 불가능합니다.
Congratulations, Manager Jang.
장 과장님, 축하드립니다.
- Congratulations. - We congratulate you.
- 축하해요. - 축하드립니다.
[Pregnancy Congratulations Song by the employees of Taehan Liquor]
[임신 축하 노래] 대한주류 임직원 일동]
Ugh, seriously, what is this?
어, 진지하게, 이게 뭐야?
Congratulations.
축하해요.
♪ Doobi dam doobi doobi dam ♪
♪ 두비댐 두비 두비댐 ♪
Seriously, why?
진심으로, 왜?
♪ Congratulations on your pregnancy ♪
♪ 임신을 축하합니다 ♪
♪ This news truly deserves celebration ♪
♪ 이 소식은 정말 축하할 만한 소식입니다 ♪
♪ We'll all celebrate for you ♪
♪우리 모두가 당신을 위해 축하하겠습니다 ♪
Congratulations!
축하합니다!
♪ But they say it was a one-night stand ♪
♪ 그런데 원나잇이었다고 하더군요 ♪
♪ What? The baby's father is ♪
♪ 뭐라고요? 아기의 아빠는 ♪
♪ The new President ♪
♪ 새로운 회장 ♪
♪ Wow, you really seduced him, like a fox ♪
♪ 와, 정말 여우처럼 그를 유혹했군요 ♪
♪ Like a fox ♪
♪ 여우처럼 ♪
♪Ha♪
♪하♪
♪ Please blow out the candles ♪
♪ 촛불을 불어주세요 ♪
♪ I'll congratulate you ♪
♪축하드려요 ♪
♪ Congratulations on your pregnancy ♪
♪ 임신을 축하합니다 ♪
Congratulations, Manager Jang.
장 과장님, 축하드립니다.
Congratulations.
축하해요.
♪Ha♪
♪하♪
♪ You deserve the congratulations ♪
♪ 당신은 축하받을 자격이 있어요 ♪
♪ You're like a fox ♪
♪ 당신은 여우 같아요 ♪
♪ Congratulations on the pregnancy ♪
♪ 임신을 축하합니다 ♪
♪Hey♪
♪안녕♪
♪Ho♪
♪호♪
Is this real?
이게 진짜인가요?
Manager Jang, will you become the mother of my child?
장과장님, 되실래요? 내 아이의 엄마?
No, this is a dream.
아니요, 이건 꿈이에요.
No!
아니요!
Ugh, what an ordeal.
아, 정말 시련이네요.
Ah, I'm dying.
아, 나 죽어가는 중이야.
When did you get here?
언제 여기에 왔나요?
Just now.
방금.
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
Yesterday you said your morning sickness was killing you and I should come.
어제 넌 입덧이라고 했어 당신을 죽이고 있었는데 나도 와야 해요.
Ah, right, I did say that.
아 맞다, 내가 그렇게 말했지.
Did you buy this?
이거 샀어?
Huh? It was hanging outside the door.
뭐? 그것은 문 밖에 걸려 있었습니다.
Wasn't it you who ordered it?
주문한 사람이 당신 아니었나요?
What?
무엇?
Your president bought this for you.
당신의 대통령이 당신을 위해 이것을 샀습니다.
I heard you had dinner together yesterday. Seems like there was some progress.
어제 같이 저녁을 먹었다고 들었어. 어느 정도 진전이 있었던 것 같습니다.
What did he say? What did your boss say?
그가 뭐라고 말했습니까? 사장님이 뭐라고 하셨어요?
Yesterday?
어제?
Nothing like that happened.
그런 일은 일어나지 않았습니다.
[Last Night] Karaoke!
[어젯밤] 노래방!
Manager.
관리자.
- I told you not to eat raw beef. - What's wrong?
- 생고기를 먹지 말라고 했잖아요. - 무슨 일이야?
Raw beef.
생 쇠고기.
Raw beef? Who ate it behind my back?
생고기? 내 뒤에서 누가 먹었어?
She said she had gastroenteritis, but she couldn't stop eating.
위장염이 있다고 하더군요. 하지만 그녀는 먹는 것을 멈출 수 없었다.
Uncle!
삼촌!
Ow.
아야.
I feel like throwing up.
토하고 싶은 기분이에요.
Se Hyeon, quickly bring a plastic bag.
세현아 빨리 비닐봉지 가져와
Yes.
예.
Team Leader, come with me.
팀 리더님, 저와 함께 가세요.
- With me... - Why me?
- 나와 함께... - 왜 나야?
Go vomit in the restroom.
화장실에 가서 토하세요.
Why did you eat so much raw beef?
생고기를 왜 그렇게 많이 먹었어요?
Do you have gastroenteritis?
위장염이 있으신가요?
What are you doing? Do you all want to watch her vomit on the street?
뭐하세요? 다들 원하시나요? 그녀가 길거리에서 토하는 걸 보려고?
You should've said you had an upset stomach.
배탈이 났다고 말했어야지.
Ugh, I feel like I'm going to throw up.
윽, 토할 것 같아.
- Oh, sorry. - Still, let me get you a taxi...
- 아, 미안해요. - 그래도 택시 태워줄게...
No, you go ahead.
아니요, 계속하세요.
Just go!
그냥 가세요!
Let's go!
갑시다!
The restroom is far. Let's take my car.
화장실이 멀다. 내 차를 가져 가자.
No, I'm feeling better now.
아니요, 이제 기분이 나아졌습니다.
We weren't caught, right?
우리는 잡히지 않았죠?
Everyone was too drunk to remember.
다들 너무 취해서 기억이 나지 않았다.
But are you really okay?
그런데 정말 괜찮으세요?
Yes.
예.
But what you said earlier.
그런데 아까 말씀하셨던 거요.
What did you mean?
무슨 뜻인가요?
Then what about taking it slow?
그럼 천천히 하는 게 어때요?
Is that not possible either?
그것도 불가능하지 않나요?
- Pardon? - Since you've decided to keep it,
- 뭐라고요? - 그대로 두기로 했으니,
I don't want to stop here.
나는 여기서 멈추고 싶지 않습니다.
I mean,
내 말은,
if you've decided to keep the baby, I'll take full responsibility.
아기를 키우기로 결정하셨다면, 제가 전적으로 책임지겠습니다.
By the way, when will you tell the company?
그런데 회사에는 언제 말해줄 거예요?
Let's just be open. You can't pretend to have gastroenteritis forever.
그냥 공개하자. 그런 척하면 안 돼 위장염이 영원히 지속됩니다.
You might not know since you're the president,
당신은 모를 수도 있습니다 당신이 대통령이니까.
but until recently I was talking about studying abroad.
하지만 최근까지 나는 얘기하고 있었어요 유학에 대해서.
If I reveal the pregnancy now,
지금 임신사실을 공개하면
there'll only be gossip.
가십만 있을 겁니다.
Even so, he'll just say he doesn't care and will take responsibility.
그래도 그 사람은 그냥 상관없다고 할 거예요. 책임을 질 것입니다.
I understand.
이해합니다.
See?
보셨나요?
Under... Huh?
아래... 응?
Pardon?
죄송해요?
You... understand?
당신은... 이해해요?
- That's it? - Yes.
- 그게 다야? - 예.
Why?
왜?
Ah, it's nothing.
아, 아무것도 아니에요.
It's late, so let's hurry up.
시간이 늦었으니 서두르자.
Progress? My foot.
진전? 내 발.
Hold on. Did you decide to keep it?
기다리다. 그것을 유지하기로 결정하셨나요?
So we can celebrate this, right?
그럼 우리 이걸 축하할 수 있겠죠?
Yeah.
응.
Jang Hui Won being a mom!
장희원이 엄마가 되었어요!
Wow, I'm so excited.
와, 정말 신난다.
Let's come up with a nickname right now.
지금 당장 별명을 생각해 봅시다.
- Nickname? - Twinkle.
- 별명? - 반짝반짝.
Glue Stick, Little Sprout.
접착제 스틱, 작은 새싹.
Ah, too ordinary.
아, 너무 평범해.
Home Run.
홈런.
This one's not great, is it?
이건 별로 좋지 않죠?
Right.
오른쪽.
- What about 'Yeol Mu'? - Yeol Mu?
- '열무'는 어떤가요? - 열무요?
Yeah, may the baby grow strong and healthy for ten months, Yeol Mu!
응, 아기가 씩씩하게 자라길 열달간 건강하게 열무님!
Cute, right?
귀엽죠?
That is pretty cute though.
그래도 꽤 귀엽습니다.
Jang Hui Won, come here. Let me hug you.
장희원 씨, 이리 오세요. 안아줄게요.
Congratulations.
축하해요.
Congratulations on becoming a mom, Jang Hui Won.
되신 걸 축하드립니다 엄마, 장희원.
Wait, Mi Ran. I think I'm going to throw up.
잠깐, 미란. 토할 것 같아요.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
Did you perhaps leave the porridge this morning?
혹시 그랬나요? 오늘 아침에 죽을 빼주시겠어요?
There was some left, so I just shared it. No need to thank me.
몇개 남아서 그냥 공유했습니다. 감사할 필요는 없습니다.
Leftover?
남은 것?
Of course it was.
물론 그렇습니다.
- Manager Jang, are you okay? - Huh?
- 장과장님, 괜찮으세요? - 뭐?
Ah, about yesterday.
아, 어제쯤.
That retching.
그 구역질.
Yes, I'm fine.
네, 괜찮아요.
You didn't get on the president's bad side, did you?
당신은 대통령 자리에 타지 않았습니다 나쁜 면이 있지, 그렇지?
Well, no...
글쎄요...
That's a huge relief.
정말 큰 안도감을 줍니다.
I mean, I was really shocked yesterday.
그러고 보니 어제 정말 충격을 받았습니다.
Why...
왜...
Anyway... get back to work.
어쨌든... 다시 일하러 가세요.
What? Leftover?
무엇? 나머지?
Leftover?
나머지?
Such an advanced conversational skill, relieving the other person's burden.
이런 고급 대화 스킬, 상대방의 부담을 덜어주는 것.
Oh, I just got a text...
아, 방금 문자가 왔어요...
Wonder what it says.
무슨 말인지 궁금합니다.
I knew it.
나는 그것을 알고 있었다.
You knew it?
알고 있었나요?
Is this right?
이게 맞나요?
Hey, gummy bear.
안녕, 젤리곰.
What's wrong with your mom?
엄마한테 무슨 문제가 있나요?
You probably heard the heartbeat.
당신은 아마도 심장 박동을 들었을 것입니다.
You scared me!
당신은 나를 겁줬어요!
What? Since when were you here?
무엇? 언제부터 여기에 있었나요?
By now, the morning sickness should be starting soon, right?
이제 입덧이 곧 시작해야지, 그렇지?
What? How do you know that so well?
무엇? 그걸 어떻게 그렇게 잘 알아?
I'm not married, but I do have two nephews.
저는 결혼하지 않았지만 조카가 두 명 있습니다.
I handled my sister's postpartum care, man. Didn't even need a caregiver.
나는 내 여동생의 산후조리를 맡았어요. 간병인도 필요하지 않았습니다.
You did?
그랬나요?
So, the types of morning sickness are...
그럼 입덧의 종류는..
What is this?
이것은 무엇입니까?
'Vomiting sickness' where you throw up even from water.
당신이 말하는 '구토병' 물 위에서도 토한다.
'Craving sickness' where you crave food all day long.
당신이 있는 곳은 '갈망병' 하루 종일 음식을 갈망합니다.
Other types include
다른 유형은 다음과 같습니다
brushing sickness, saliva sickness, vegetable sickness, smell sickness, etc.
양치질병, 타액병, 식물병, 냄새병 등
What's 'saliva sickness'?
'타액병'이란?
Oh, 'saliva sickness.' That's a great question.
아, '침병'. 좋은 질문입니다.
I love such detailed questions.
저는 이렇게 세세한 질문을 좋아해요.
'Saliva sickness' means
'타액병'이란
the morning sickness is so severe that
입덧이 너무 심해서
[Feels nauseated swallowing their own saliva] swallowing your own saliva feels disgusting.
[스스로 침을 삼키며 메스꺼움을 느낀다] 자신의 침을 삼키는 것은 역겨운 느낌입니다.
Trying to swallow it
삼키려고 노력 중
[Triggers vomiting] actually triggers vomiting.
[구토 유발] 실제로 구토를 유발합니다.
This is completely insane, you know.
이건 완전히 미친짓이에요.
For severe morning sickness,
심한 입덧의 경우,
it's recommended to find your own safe foods.
자신만의 안전한 식품을 찾는 것이 좋습니다.
Bananas, cold noodles, plums, strawberries, ice cream, ice, sports drinks,
바나나, 냉면, 자두, 딸기, 아이스크림, 얼음, 스포츠 음료,
sparkling water, and so on.
탄산수 등등.
Some people said these helped their morning sickness.
어떤 사람들은 이것이 도움이 되었다고 말했습니다. 그들의 입덧.
But here's the thing.
하지만 여기에 문제가 있습니다.
In my sister's case, after countless trials of eating and vomiting,
내 여동생의 경우에는 셀 수 없이 많은 끝에 먹고 토하는 시험,
the only thing
유일한 것
she could eat comfortably was tangerines.
그녀가 편하게 먹을 수 있는 것은 귤이었다.
Tangerines.
감귤.
What?
무엇?
What do you think? Isn't that inspiring?
어떻게 생각하나요? 감동적이지 않나요?
Yeah, that's good.
네, 좋습니다.
Tangerines.
감귤.
- Manager Jang. - Oh, you startled me.
- 장과장님. - 아, 깜짝 놀랐어요.
Perfect timing.
완벽한 타이밍.
Were you waiting for me?
나를 기다리고 있었나요?
No way.
안 돼요.
By any chance, do you like tangerines?
혹시, 귤 좋아하시나요?
I happen to know someone who runs a big tangerine farm in Jeju.
우연히 달리는 사람을 알아요 제주의 한 대형 감귤 농장.
No,
아니요,
I don't like them.
나는 그들을 좋아하지 않는다.
But...
하지만...
Most people like tangerines though.
하지만 대부분의 사람들은 귤을 좋아합니다.
Why? Do you have a ton of leftover tangerines?
왜? 당신은 가지고 있습니까? 남은 귤이 잔뜩?
Enough to start sharing them with me?
나와 공유하기 시작하면 충분합니까?
No, that's not it.
아니요, 그게 아닙니다.
President, do eat a lot.
대통령님, 많이 드세요.
I have a meeting now, so I should get going.
지금 회의가 있어서 가봐야 해요.
Wait...
잠깐...
Don't give me any info from now on, got it?
이제부터 아무 정보도 주지 마세요, 알겠죠?
Eat all these tangerines today.
오늘은 이 귤을 다 먹어보세요.
Ugh, seriously.
아, 정말요.
That's annoying.
짜증나네요.
[Premium Tangerines] No...
[프리미엄 감귤] 아니...
Sister.
언니.
Tangerines...
귤...
Stop by after work before heading home.
퇴근 후 집에 가기 전에 들러보세요.
This massage is perfect for blood circulation and relaxation.
이 마사지는 다음과 같은 경우에 적합합니다. 혈액 순환과 휴식.
Jang Hui Won, Jang Hui Won.
장희원, 장희원.
How are you feeling? Did you eat anything?
기분이 어때요? 뭐라도 먹었어?
No, eating makes me queasy, so better come on an empty stomach.
아니, 먹으면 속이 메스껍다. 그러니 공복에 오는 것이 좋습니다.
Oh, no.
안 돼.
Here.
여기.
[Hwang Mi Ran]
[황미란]
But can I use what you won from the event?
그런데 이벤트에서 당첨된 것을 사용해도 될까요?
Of course.
물론.
Just in case, tell them to avoid your stomach and focus on your chest and above.
혹시라도 배를 피하라고 전해 가슴과 그 위에 집중하세요.
And don't forget to use my name when you go in.
그리고 사용하는 것을 잊지 마세요 들어갈 때 내 이름.
It's over there. Let's go, let's go.
저기 있어요. 가자, 가자.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Ma'am, I'll bring you a face mask.
선생님, 마스크 가져다 드릴께요.
You reserved it through the event today, right, Ms. Hwang Mi Ran?
오늘 이벤트를 통해 예약해주셨는데요, 그렇죠 황미란씨?
Yes, that's me, Hwang Mi Ran.
네, 저 황미란이에요.
Okay, we'll begin now.
좋아요, 이제 시작하겠습니다.
Relax and make yourself comfortable.
긴장을 풀고 편안하게 지내십시오.
Sorry, but it's a bit chilly.
죄송하지만 좀 추워요.
Could you raise the room temperature a little?
방을 올려주실 수 있나요? 온도가 좀?
Oh, are you cold?
아, 추워요?
Just a moment.
잠시만요.
That's what I wanted to say, thank you for saying it for me.
그게 내가 말하고 싶었던 거야, 나에게 말해줘서 고마워요.
I noticed you were cold.
나는 당신이 추운 것을 알아차렸습니다.
I'd enjoy a warmer treatment too.
나도 따뜻한 대우를 받고 싶다.
How thoughtful, really.
정말 사려 깊습니다.
You must've come straight after work, huh?
퇴근하고 바로 오셨나봐요?
Is work not too demanding?
일은 너무 힘든 일이 아닌가?
No, it's fun because it's what I love.
아니요, 제가 좋아하는 것이기 때문에 재미있습니다.
Turning your passion into a career couldn't have been easy.
당신의 열정을 직업으로 바꾸세요 쉬웠을 리가 없습니다.
So I consider myself lucky and work happily.
그래서 저는 운이 좋다고 생각하고 행복하게 일해요.
Ah, and maybe because I'm ambitious, I also enjoy the sense of accomplishment.
아, 그리고 아마도 내가 야망이 있어서일지도 모르지만 성취감도 즐깁니다.
That kind of mindset is quite rare.
그런 사고방식은 정말 드물어요.
Would it be rude to ask your age?
나이를 묻는 것은 실례일까요?
I'm thirty this year.
나는 올해 서른 살이다.
Hmm, a four-year age gap.
흠, 4살의 나이차이가 나네요.
Perfect, just perfect.
완벽해요, 그냥 완벽해요.
So, are you married?
그럼 결혼하셨나요?
- Pardon? - What's your religion?
- 뭐라고요? - 당신의 종교는 무엇입니까?
Not seeing anyone?
아무도 안 만나요?
What do your parents do?
부모님은 무엇을 하시나요?
Ah, well...
아, 글쎄...
[Staff Profile]
[직원 프로필]
You know this isn't allowed, right?
이건 허용되지 않는 거 아시죠?
Huh? Yeah.
뭐? 응.
[Staff Profile] Let's see...
[직원 프로필] 어디 보자 ...
[Hwang Mi Ran] Found her, Hwang Mi Ran.
[황미란] 찾았다, 황미란.
Her father is a director at Haemo Group.
그녀의 아버지는 해모그룹의 이사이다.
But why would she work at our hotel?
그런데 그 사람이 왜 우리 호텔에서 일하겠어요?
What's this for?
이것은 무엇을 위한 것입니까?
Seems like her mother passed away early.
어머니가 일찍 돌아가신 것 같습니다.
Seeing how well she grew up with one parent,
그녀가 한 부모 밑에서 얼마나 잘 자랐는지를 보면,
she must've matured early.
그녀는 일찍 성숙했나봐.
- Mother. - Huh?
- 어머니. - 뭐?
Are you planning to arrange a blind date for Du Jun?
정리할 계획인가 두준의 소개팅?
Oh.
오.
No, it's not...
아니, 그렇지 않아...
I just checked out of curiosity, nothing serious.
방금 궁금해서 확인해봤는데, 심각하지 않습니다.
Anyway, thanks.
어쨌든 고마워요.
With autumn approaching,
가을이 다가오면서,
how about a business targeting campers?
캠핑족을 대상으로 하는 사업은 어떻습니까?
[Taehan Beer, Camping Season Companion]
[대한맥주, 캠핑의 계절 동행]
Taehan Beer has a smooth taste
대한맥주는 맛이 부드럽다
that goes well with Korean food
한국 음식과 잘 어울리는 것 같아요
or strong seasonings.
아니면 강한 양념.
So this time, I suggest pairing it with camping food.
그래서 이번에는 페어링을 제안합니다 캠핑음식으로
Meal kits are really popular these days.
요즘 밀키트가 정말 인기가 많아요.
Collaborating with them could work well.
그들과 협력하면 잘 될 수 있습니다.
Right, and a collab using special sauces from famous chefs
맞습니다. 그리고 다음을 사용한 공동 작업은 유명 셰프의 특별한 소스
like Jung Ji Sun would be great.
정지선처럼 하면 좋을 것 같다.
Camping food has many varieties. Any examples?
캠핑음식은 종류가 많습니다. 어떤 예가 있나요?
[Camping food] Barbecue, which is a must for camping.
[캠핑음식] 캠핑에 꼭 필요한 바베큐.
Barbecue or smoked saus...
바베큐나 훈제 소시지...
Sorry.
죄송합니다.
Smoked sausages or pork tro...
훈제 소시지나 돼지고기...
Pork?
돼지고기?
Pork...
돼지고기...
- What, did you just swear? - I think she said pork trotters.
- 뭐야, 방금 욕했어? - 족발이라고 한 것 같아요.
Pork trotters.
돼지 족발.
[Camping food] Yeah, right, that.
[캠핑음식] 응, 맞아, 그거.
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
Wow, pork trotters!
와, 돼지 족발!
Doesn't that sound delicious?
맛있을 것 같지 않니?
Pork trotters with Taehan Beer!
대한맥주와 족발!
Oh, how about some merchandise for our brand?
아, 우리 브랜드 상품은 어때요?
Something like a cooler to keep our beer chilled.
쿨러같은거 맥주를 차갑게 유지하기 위해.
Exactly, a cooler.
바로, 쿨러입니다.
A cooler.
쿨러.
Good idea.
좋은 생각이에요.
Manager, how old did you say your eldest is?
매니저님, 큰 아이가 몇 살이라고 했어요?
Ah, now in 8th grade.
아, 이제 8학년이군요.
He's going through a stormy adolescent phase.
그는 폭풍우가 치는 청소년기를 겪고 있습니다.
No one can approach him.
누구도 그에게 접근할 수 없습니다.
Already in middle school?
벌써 중학교에 다니나요?
They say others' kids grow up fast. That's so true.
남의 아이들은 빨리 자란다고 하더라고요. 그건 정말 사실이에요.
Still, Manager Nah, you always brag about your kids.
그래도 나과장님은 늘 당신의 아이들에 대해 자랑하세요.
Right, you call them all the time whenever you have a chance.
그렇죠, 당신은 그들에게 항상 전화해요 기회가 있을 때마다.
Nah!
아니!
I wasn't bragging.
나는 자랑하지 않았습니다.
A few days ago, my second kid went out
며칠 전 둘째 아이가 나갔다.
fully geared for inline skating but came back crying.
인라인 스케이트에 완벽하게 맞춰져 있습니다. 그런데 울면서 돌아왔다.
- Why? - When I asked what happened,
- 왜? - 무슨 일이냐고 물으니,
he said his helmet wouldn't come off.
헬멧이 벗겨지지 않을 거라고 하더군요.
Then he threw a fit blaming me, and I barely calmed him down!
그러다가 그는 나를 비난하면서 발작을 일으켰습니다. 그리고 나는 그를 간신히 진정시켰습니다!
Look at me.
나를 봐.
- Is my head big? - Yes.
- 내 머리가 큰가요? - 예.
- Really?
- 정말?
- Oh come on! - Seriously.
- 아 어서! - 진지하게.
Oh, that's so funny I'm tearing up.
아 너무 웃겨서 눈물이 나네요.
I need the restroom.
화장실이 필요해요.
Is this story that sad?
이 이야기가 그렇게 슬픈가요?
Your son had a real reason to cry, though.
하지만 당신의 아들은 울어야 할 진짜 이유가 있었습니다.
Seriously.
진지하게.
I told you not to act like we know each other at work.
그런 식으로 행동하지 말라고 했잖아 우리는 직장에서 서로를 알고 있습니다.
What urgent matter is it?
무슨 긴급한 일이에요?
No, it's not urgent, but...
아니, 급한 건 아니지만...
I'm asking as your uncle now.
나는 지금 당신의 삼촌으로서 묻고 있습니다.
I'm just curious if work's manageable,
업무가 원활하게 진행되는지 궁금합니다.
if there are difficulties,
어려움이 있으면,
or if you need anything.
아니면 필요한 게 있으면요.
Work is completely manageable, and there's nothing particularly hard.
작업은 완전히 관리 가능하며, 그리고 특별히 어려운 점은 없습니다.
And whenever I need something, you just buy it for me.
그리고 뭔가 필요할 때마다, 그냥 나를 위해 사세요.
What's this about all of a sudden?
갑자기 이게 무슨 소리야?
Feeling guilty about only giving attention to Manager Jang?
죄책감을 느끼는 것만으로도 장과장에게 주목?
No, what are you talking about?
아니, 무슨 소리 하는 거야?
To me, you're always number one.
나에게 있어 당신은 언제나 1순위입니다.
Oh, how nice.
아, 정말 좋네요.
I mean it.
진심이에요.
Ah, come on.
아, 어서.
Stop beating around the bush. What's going on?
덤불 주위를 두드리는 것을 중지하십시오. 무슨 일이야?
Want me to ask Manager something?
매니저한테 뭐 좀 물어볼까?
That's not what I meant,
내 말은 그런 뜻이 아니었는데,
but if you insist.
하지만 당신이 주장한다면.
Why am I like this? Why do I keep crying?
내가 왜 이럴까? 왜 계속 울어요?
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
Oh, yes.
아, 그렇죠.
The morning sickness,
입덧,
I only saw it in dramas, but it must be really tough.
드라마에서만 봤었는데, 하지만 정말 힘들겠다.
Is there any particular dish you're craving or would like to eat?
특별한 요리가 있나요? 갈망하고 있거나 먹고 싶나요?
I thought I could recommend a lunch menu today.
추천할 수 있을 것 같았어요 오늘 점심메뉴.
Something I'm craving...
내가 갈망하는 것...
[Jjampong]
[짬뽕]
Jjampong!
짬뽕!
For some reason, I think I could eat that.
왠지 먹을 수 있을 것 같아요.
Thank you for coming all this way.
여기까지 와주셔서 감사합니다.
I couldn't forget the taste of the sugar-glazed sweet potatoes I had.
그 맛을 잊을 수가 없었어요 제가 먹은 설탕을 입힌 고구마에요.
I'm the grateful one.
나는 감사한 사람이다.
That sales boost you gave us was huge.
당신이 우리에게 준 판매 증가는 엄청났습니다.
Next time, I'll make sure to boost the sales even more.
다음에는 꼭 확인할게요 매출을 더욱 높이기 위해.
Then, I'll leave it in your hands today.
그럼 오늘은 여러분의 손에 맡기겠습니다.
- Thank you. - Um,
- 감사합니다. - 음,
may I give you a hand?
제가 도와드릴까요?
I used to be pretty skilled with knives back in the day.
나는 꽤 능숙했었어 옛날에는 칼로.
My forearms...
내 팔뚝...
Oh, they're covered, so you can't see them.
아, 가려져 있어서 안보이네요.
These muscles were built from knife work.
이 근육은 칼 작업으로 만들어졌습니다.
Want me to show some skill?
실력 좀 보여드릴까요?
Please don't.
그러지 마세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
Cooking isn't done brutishly by force.
요리는 강제로 잔인하게 이루어지지 않습니다.
It's about wrist flick, like Chef here.
여기 셰프처럼 손목을 튕기는 동작에 관한 것입니다.
Not easy.
쉽지 않습니다.
- Is she angry? - It's because of you.
- 화가 났나요? - 너 때문이야.
Stop showing off.
그만 과시하세요.
Showing off?
과시?
[Try the Chinese Cuisine Queen's special lunch at Taehan]
[중국요리 퀸즈를 맛보세요 대한에서의 특별한 점심]
[Taehan and a celebrity chef, a delicious encounter]
[태한과 연예인 셰프, 맛있는 만남]
[The Chinese Cuisine Queen visits Taehan Liquor]
[중식의 여왕 대한주류를 방문합니다]
[A gourmet journey to China at work? Taehan makes it possible]
[직장에서 중국으로 미식여행? 태한이가 만든다]
[Dim sum]
[딤섬]
[Lobster jjampong]
[랍스터 짬뽕]
[Stir-fried seafood and vegetables]
[해산물과 야채볶음]
[Sugar-glazed sweet potatoes]
[설탕고구마]
[The Chinese Cuisine Queen] Alright.
[중식의 여왕] 알았어.
Today's lunch is
오늘 점심은
a special event prepared by
에서 준비한 특별한 이벤트
the President and Chef Jung Ji Sun
정지선 사장 겸 셰프
for our hardworking staff.
열심히 일하는 우리 직원들을 위해.
We hope you enjoy it!
우리는 당신이 그것을 즐기시기 바랍니다!
What's the occasion today?
오늘은 어떤 행사인가요?
Chef Jung Ji Sun is at our cafeteria?
정지선 셰프가 우리 식당에 있어요?
Our president is generous!
우리 대통령은 관대합니다!
Sugar-glazed sweet potatoes, stir-fried seafood and vegetables,
설탕을 입힌 고구마, 해산물과 야채를 볶은 요리,
lobster jjampong, even dim sum!
랍스터 짬뽕, 심지어 딤섬까지!
You said earlier you wanted jjampong.
아까 짬뽕이 먹고 싶다고 했잖아.
The menu is exactly Chinese food.
메뉴는 바로 중국음식이다.
Right.
오른쪽.
For our intern, an extra lobster! Thank you.
우리 인턴을 위해 랍스터를 추가로! 감사합니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
And for Manager Jang, specially, an extra lobster.
그리고 장과장님의 경우, 특히 랍스터 한 마리 더.
Oh, I'm sorry... I can't eat it.
아, 미안해요... 못 먹겠어요.
Manager Jang?
장 과장?
Oh, my! Two whole lobsters per person? Such luxury!
아, 이런! 랍스터 두 마리가 통째로 사람마다? 이런 럭셔리함!
There aren't many left, so I think we have to stop giving them out. Sorry.
남은 게 많지 않아서 그런 것 같아요. 우리는 그것들을 배포하는 것을 중단해야 합니다. 죄송합니다.
Yes.
예.
Are you really that worried about her?
정말 그 사람이 그렇게 걱정되나요?
She's suffering from morning sickness. I can't just pretend not to notice.
그녀는 입덧을 앓고 있습니다. 그냥 눈치채지 못한 척 할 수가 없어요.
This is just consideration and goodwill.
이것은 단지 배려와 선의일 뿐입니다.
Oh, yeah?
아, 그래요?
So is that the end of your goodwill?
그럼 그게 당신의 선의의 끝인가요?
I don't know. What am I supposed to do?
모르겠습니다. 나는 무엇을 해야 합니까?
With this kind of thing, details matter more than grand gestures.
이런식으로 디테일하게 거창한 몸짓보다 더 중요하다.
No wonder you're a chaebol heir.
당신이 재벌 상속자인 것도 당연합니다.
It needs sincerity.
진심이 필요합니다.
Sincerity?
성실?
Jujube tea.
대추차.
Wow, retro vibes.
와, 레트로한 느낌이군요.
Is this the welcome drink for Hanok Village?
이게 한옥마을의 웰컴 드링크인가요?
When I was little, whenever I had a cold or an upset stomach,
어렸을 때, 그럴 때마다 감기에 걸렸거나 속이 쓰렸는데,
my mom would make me lots of jujube tea syrup drinks.
엄마가 나한테 해줄게 대추차 시럽 음료가 많아요.
I looked it up, and they say it's good for morning sickness and boosting immunity.
찾아봤는데 괜찮다고 하네요 입덧과 면역력 강화.
Yeah, that's so thoughtful. This is exactly what I mean by details.
응, 정말 사려 깊구나. 이것이 바로 세부 사항을 의미하는 것입니다.
That's quite a lot, good luck.
꽤 많군요. 행운을 빕니다.
Where are you going? You have to do this with me.
어디 가세요? 이 일은 나와 함께 해야 합니다.
I'm allergic to jujubes, seriously.
나는 심각하게 대추에 알레르기가 있습니다.
Allergic to jujubes? You're joking, right?
대추에 알레르기가 있나요? 농담하는 거죠?
Want me to give you another allergy too?
또 다른 알레르기도 알려드릴까요?
Where should we start?
어디서부터 시작해야 할까요?
Shake it off, this first.
털어내세요, 우선 이것부터요.
Looks like this is going to be a busy one.
이번 일은 바쁜 일이 될 것 같습니다.
Manager Jang hasn't come back?
장과장님은 아직 안 돌아오셨나요?
Did she go to the hospital or something?
그녀는 병원에 갔나요?
What on earth did she eat to get gastroenteritis?
도대체 그녀는 무엇을 먹었나요? 위장염에 걸리려면?
I heard she ate bad raw oysters.
맛없는 생굴을 먹었다고 들었어요.
Norovirus?
노로바이러스?
Wow, I hear that's no joke?
와, 농담이 아니라고 들었는데?
If it's severe, you have to be hospitalized and get an IV drip. It's that bad.
심하면 병원에 입원해야 그리고 IV 주사를 맞으세요. 정말 나쁘다.
Shouldn't we report the place if it got her that sick?
장소를 신고해야 하지 않겠습니까? 그 사람이 그렇게 아프다면?
Making someone that sick!
사람을 그렇게 아프게 만들어!
Should I just report them?
그냥 신고해야 하나요?
Please just pretend you don't know anything.
제발 아무것도 모르는 척해주세요.
Did she really
그녀가 정말 그랬나요?
come down with norovirus?
노로바이러스에 걸리나요?
Then what could it be?
그렇다면 그것은 무엇일까요?
Hangover!
숙취!
Ah, probably not that.
아, 아마 그렇지 않을 것입니다.
Manager Jang has a perfectly healthy liver.
장과장님은 간이 완벽하게 건강하십니다.
Could there be some story she can't tell us?
그녀가 우리에게 말할 수 없는 이야기가 있는 것은 아닐까?
Oh, what could there possibly be?
아, 뭐가 있겠어?
No, there might be something.
아니, 뭔가 있을 수도 있습니다.
Like with the Germany study program last time,
독일과 마찬가지로 지난번 학습 프로그램,
she's been very suspicious lately.
그녀는 최근에 매우 의심스러워요.
So, for the urgent matters first,
그러니 우선 급한 일부터
the analysis of the first-half of next year's liquor market trends.
내년 상반기 분석 주류시장 동향.
You two divide the work
둘이서 일을 나누어라
and handle it properly.
그리고 제대로 처리하세요.
- Yes.
- 예.
Do you like Hui Won or something?
희원 좋아하시나요?
What? I'm just worried she might meet some weirdo.
뭐? 걱정이 될 뿐이야 그 사람이 이상한 사람을 만날 수도 있어요.
You two handle this.
너희 둘이서 이 일을 처리해라.
Yes.
예.
Assistant Manager Cha.
차 대리.
Yes?
예?
Oh.
오.
Yes, I understand.
네, 이해합니다.
And besides managing existing clients,
기존 고객 관리 외에도
you all know we need to develop new client relationships too, right?
우리가 발전해야 한다는 건 다들 아시죠? 새로운 고객 관계도 마찬가지죠?
Yes.
예.
Shouldn't the sales team get some applause too?
영업팀은 안되나요? 박수도 좀 받아?
Ah.
아.
Why do my eyes just want to close after eating?
왜 내 눈은 그냥 식사 후에 문을 닫고 싶나요?
I need to wake up a bit.
좀 일어나야 해요.
Oh, Assistant Manager Cha!
아, 차대리님!
- Oh. - It's been a while.
- 오. - 오랜만이에요.
Manager, how have you been?
매니저님, 그동안 잘 지내셨나요?
What brings you to our floor?
우리 층에 무슨 일로 오셨나요?
Oh...
아...
Here to see Manager Jang?
장과장님 만나러 오셨나요?
We're starting the trend analysis for the first-half of next year soon.
추세 분석을 시작하겠습니다 이제 곧 내년 상반기.
So I thought she might have some helpful materials.
그래서 나는 그녀가 그럴 수도 있다고 생각했어요 도움이 되는 자료가 있어요.
Oh, Assistant Manager Cha, as expected.
아, 차대리님, 역시 그렇군요.
So that's why you are so close with Manager Jang.
그래서 네가 그렇게 가까이 있는 거야 장과장과 함께.
Do aces just understand each other?
에이스는 서로를 이해하는 걸까요?
If you keep buttering me up like that, I might actually believe it.
계속 그렇게 나한테 욕먹으면 실제로 믿을 수도 있겠네요.
I'm just working hard.
나는 단지 열심히 일하고 있습니다.
What? Humble too?
무엇? 겸손도요?
I'm jealous of you, Assistant Manager Cha.
부럽습니다 차대리님.
By the way, is everything okay with Manager Jang?
그런데, 괜찮나요? 장과장이랑?
She can't seem to focus and seems sick often.
그녀는 집중을 못하는 것 같고 자주 아픈 것 같습니다.
Is that so?
그렇습니까?
I haven't heard anything.
나는 아무것도 듣지 못했습니다.
Hui Won works so hard, that's probably why.
희원이가 너무 열심히 일해서 그런가 봐요.
She's a workaholic, you know.
그 사람은 워커홀릭이에요.
Yeah? Well, if nothing's wrong, that's good.
응? 뭐, 별 일 없으면 다행이군요.
Ah, then I'll head down first.
아, 그럼 먼저 내려갈게요.
Yes, please go ahead.
예, 계속 진행해 주세요.
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
If you're going to scold me, do it later.
나한테 혼날 거면 나중에 해라.
I don't even have the energy to get scolded today.
기운도 없어 오늘 혼내려고.
Am I someone who scolds you every day?
나는 매일 당신을 꾸짖는 사람입니까?
I'm worried.
걱정된다.
But this boyfriend of yours...
그런데 이 남자친구는...
Oh, sorry.
아, 미안해요.
Hey, here.
안녕, 여기.
If it's tough, want to go to the hospital?
힘들면 병원에 가볼까?
No, it's just the morning sickness.
아니요, 그냥 입덧이에요.
Let's go get a prescription for that.
처방전 받으러 가자.
I'll go with you.
나는 당신과 함께 갈 것이다.
If someone sees us, they might misunderstand. I'll handle it myself.
누군가 우리를 본다면 그럴지도 몰라 오해하다. 내가 직접 처리하겠습니다.
You said you could handle it, but you seem off.
당신은 그것을 감당할 수 있다고 말했고, 그런데 당신은 별로인 것 같아요.
Here.
여기.
Hold on to it properly.
제대로 붙잡으세요.
Don't spill it.
그것을 흘리지 마십시오.
Oh.
오.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Call me if it gets hard.
힘들면 전화해.
Even at dawn.
새벽에도.
Got it.
알았어요.
Go quickly.
빨리 가세요.
That male friend worked at our company?
그 남자 친구가 우리 회사에 다녔어요?
Oh my, I went all out washing the jujubes
아놔 대추 씻느라 혼났어
and now my whole body aches.
이제 온몸이 아프네요.
You know I shed my blood, sweat, and tears for that jujube syrup, right?
내가 피, 땀, 흘린거 알지? 그리고 그 대추 시럽 때문에 눈물이 나죠?
Try putting some real effort into me instead of everyone else.
나에게 진짜 노력을 좀 해보세요 다른 사람 대신.
If I'm choosing, I want grand gestures, not details.
내가 선택한다면, 나는 원한다 세부 사항이 아닌 웅장한 제스처.
You know, something big. That kind of thing.
뭔가 큰 일이 있군요. 그런 것.
Are you even listening?
당신도 듣고 있나요?
The report.
보고서.
The report?
보고서?
The report is really not good.
보고서가 정말 좋지 않습니다.
I thought it was fine.
나는 그것이 괜찮다고 생각했다.
No.
아니요.
From beginning to end, there isn't a single part I like.
처음부터 끝까지, 마음에 드는 부분이 하나도 없어요.
- Get the person in charge to redo it... - No.
- 담당자에게 재작업을 요청하세요. - 아니.
No need for that.
그럴 필요는 없습니다.
I know someone who's perfectly suited for this job.
나는 어떤 사람을 알고 있다. 이 직업에 완벽하게 적합해요.
You wanted to see me?
나를 보고 싶었나요?
Assistant Manager Cha Min Uk?
차민욱 대리요?
I heard you are famous in the sales team for being diligent and meticulous.
영업팀에서 유명하다고 들었는데 부지런하고 꼼꼼하기 때문이죠.
They say you're the king of organization.
당신이 조직의 왕이라고 하잖아요.
Oh.
오.
And?
그리고?
The reports from the sales team sometimes feel rough, so I was curious.
영업팀의 보고서 가끔은 거친 느낌이 들어서 궁금했어요.
I wondered just how meticulous your reports would be.
얼마나 꼼꼼한지 궁금했어요 당신의 보고서는 그럴 것입니다.
Well,
글쎄,
it can be done by the end of this week, right?
그것은 할 수 있다 이번주 말까지죠?
This week...
이번주...
All of these?
이것들 모두?
Yes.
예.
Yes, I understand.
네, 이해합니다.
Oh.
오.
I hope I'm not taking time away from your date, Assistant Manager Cha.
시간을 낭비하지 않기를 바라요 당신의 데이트에서 차 대리.
Oh.
오.
I don't have a girlfriend.
나는 여자 친구가 없습니다.
Is that so?
그렇습니까?
That's surprising. You're quite good-looking.
정말 놀랍습니다. 당신은 꽤 잘 생겼어요.
Well then.
그럼.
And perhaps,
그리고 아마도,
is there someone you like?
좋아하는 사람 있어?
You don't have anyone you like either?
너도 좋아하는 사람 없어?
Pardon?
뭐라고요?
Is he complimenting me? Or picking a fight?
그 사람이 나를 칭찬하고 있는 걸까? 아니면 싸움을 선택합니까?
He's a bit odd.
그 사람 좀 이상해요.
Are you handling all the company work by yourself?
처리하고 있나요? 회사는 다 혼자 일해요?
Wow.
우와.
Work really should be done like Assistant Manager Cha does it, right?
일은 진짜로 해야 해 차 대리가 그러는 것처럼요?
Wow, nice, yeah.
와, 좋아요, 그렇죠.
Ms. Ye Jin, Ms. Ye Jin!
예진씨, 예진씨!
The weather's gloomy today.
오늘은 날씨가 우울해요.
- Did everyone bring an umbrella? - Is it supposed to rain today?
- 다들 우산을 가져오셨나요? - 오늘 비가 올까요?
I have one at the office.
사무실에 하나 있어요.
I'm fine. I plan to go for a run after work today.
잘 지내요. 나는 갈 계획이다 오늘 퇴근 후 달리기 위해.
What? They say it's going to rain heavily.
무엇? 비가 많이 올 것이라고 합니다.
Ah, haven't you heard of the 'rain-run' trend these days?
아, 못 들었어? 요즘 'rain-run' 트렌드는요?
- You gotta run when you can run. - Look at that.
- 달릴 수 있을 때 달려야 해요. - 저것 좀 보세요.
Tak Soo is so passionate.
탁수씨는 정말 열정적이에요.
- What about Assistant Manager Choi? - Of course I have one.
- 최 대리는 어떻습니까? -물론 있어요.
If I don't bring it, who else is going to?
내가 안 가져오면 또 누가 가져가나요?
On a rainy day like this,
이렇게 비오는 날에는
is there no man to get wet in the rain with me instead of just using an umbrella?
비에 젖을 사람 없나요 그냥 우산을 쓰는 대신 나랑 같이 갈래?
Nope, none. And you'll catch a cold.
아뇨, 없어요. 그리고 당신은 감기에 걸릴 것입니다.
This isn't romance. It's turning into a disaster movie.
이건 로맨스가 아닙니다. 재난영화로 변해가고 있습니다.
Manager, your way of thinking is really...
매니저님 사고방식이 정말...
Be honest.
솔직해지세요.
Your wife scolded you a lot when you were dating, right?
아내가 당신을 많이 혼냈어요 너 데이트할 때 그랬지?
No, she was totally into me.
아니, 그 사람은 나한테 완전 빠져 있었어.
Hey, Manager Jang! Do you have an umbrella?
안녕하세요 장과장님! 우산 있어요?
- Is it raining? - They said it'll rain heavily tonight.
- 비가 오나요? - 오늘 밤에 비가 많이 올 거라고 하더군요.
Looks like I'll need to leave on the dot today.
떠나야 할 것 같아 오늘 점에.
I didn't even bring an umbrella.
우산도 안 가지고 왔어요.
Is Manager Jang still feeling unwell from the norovirus?
장과장님 아직도 몸이 안 좋으신가요 노로바이러스 때문에?
Even so, her pale skin looks even paler.
그럼에도 불구하고 그녀의 창백한 피부는 더욱 창백해 보인다.
She used to pull three all-nighters, but now she's leaving early.
그녀는 세 번 밤을 새곤 했고, 하지만 지금은 일찍 떠나는 중이에요.
Are you having a meeting or just chatting?
회의 중이신가요, 아니면 그냥 채팅 중이신가요?
Team Leader, did you bring an umbrella?
팀장님, 우산은 가져오셨나요?
They said it's supposed to rain heavily tonight.
그럴 거라고 하더군요 오늘 밤에는 비가 많이 내릴 예정입니다.
Why? Should I use yours, Manager Nah?
왜? 나 매니저님, 당신 것을 사용해야 할까요?
I'm really sorry. I only have one myself.
정말 죄송해요. 나 자신은 딱 하나밖에 없어요.
Unless you're going to hand over yours or stop the rain yourself,
당신이 당신의 것을 넘겨주지 않는 한 아니면 스스로 비를 멈추거나,
stop worrying about the weather and get back to work.
날씨 걱정은 이제 그만 그리고 다시 일하러 가세요.
Is there someone you like?
좋아하는 사람 있어요?
You don't have anyone you like either?
너도 좋아하는 사람 없어?
Childish. So childish.
어린애 같은. 너무 유치해요.
What, are you a kindergartener?
뭐야, 너 유치원생이니?
No way, did you hear that?
아니, 그거 들었어?
Instead of doing your work, you were eavesdropping outside? Jeez.
당신의 일을 하는 대신, 밖에서 엿듣고 있었어? 이런.
Since when did you summon employees separately to assign work?
언제부터 소환했어? 직원들이 별도로 업무를 할당하나요?
Just because he's close with Manager Jang.
그냥 장과장님이랑 친하니까.
What did Assistant Manager Cha do wrong?
차대리가 무슨 잘못을 했나요?
It seems like you've got some misunderstanding.
당신이 가지고있는 것 같습니다 약간의 오해.
Core talents of the company are always under special management.
회사의 핵심인재 항상 특별 관리를 받고 있습니다.
He's famous in the sales team for being diligent and meticulous.
그 사람은 영업팀에서 유명해요 부지런하고 꼼꼼하기 때문이죠.
And it's only natural for a president to show interest in employees.
그리고 그것은 대통령으로서 당연한 일이다. 직원들에게 관심을 보이기 위해.
Should I just ignore it?
그냥 무시해야 할까요?
Oh, is that so?
아, 그런가?
Then why don't you pay some attention to me, who's stuck by your side all day, huh?
그럼 나한테 좀 관심을 가져주는 게 어때? 하루 종일 네 옆에 붙어 있는 사람이 누구야?
My birthday's coming up.
내 생일이 다가오고 있어요.
Oh, wait a second.
아, 잠깐만요.
This is a bit sensitive.
이건 좀 민감해요.
You don't know my birthday, do you?
당신은 내 생일을 모르죠?
Come on, how long have we known each other?
자, 우리가 알고 지낸 지 얼마나 됐나요?
October...
10월...
21st, right?
21일 맞죠?
Wow.
우와.
I suspected it, but still...
의심했지만 그래도...
It's the 25th.
25일이에요.
October 25th.
10월 25일.
This is annoying.
이것은 짜증나는 일이다.
You keep calling me Secretary Go.
계속 고비서라고 부르시네요.
But you do remember my name, right?
하지만 내 이름은 기억하지?
Why would you say something that hurtful?
왜 그렇게 상처받는 말을 하겠어요?
You're talking nonsense.
넌 말도 안되는 소리를 하고 있어.
You!
너!
You're acting unlike yourself, that's why.
당신은 자신과 다르게 행동하고 있기 때문에 그렇습니다.
Ugh, I don't know what's so special about you
아, 당신의 특별한 점이 무엇인지 모르겠어요
that I have to drive you home on a rainy day like this.
내가 당신을 집까지 데려다줘야 한다고 이런 비오는 날에.
It's raining outside now?
지금 밖에 비가 내리고 있나요?
It's been raining for a while.
한동안 비가 내렸습니다.
Why? Do you have business with the New Product Development Team?
왜? 사업이 있나요? 신제품 개발팀과는?
Just checking if our company's core departments and key talents
우리 회사가 맞는지 확인해 보세요. 핵심부서 및 핵심인재
are preparing to leave work properly.
제대로 퇴근 준비 중입니다.
Wait, do you even care about when I leave work?
잠깐만요, 혹시 신경 쓰이시나요? 내가 퇴근할 때?
Hey, hold on.
이봐, 잠깐만.
Don't tell me...
말하지 마세요 ...
You're worried Manager Jang might not have an umbrella?
걱정되시죠 장과장님 우산이 없지 않을까?
You didn't care when I got completely soaked.
내가 완전히 흠뻑 젖어도 당신은 신경 쓰지 않았습니다.
Just check real quick and leave right away.
빨리 확인하고 바로 떠나세요.
I'll head home on my own.
나는 나 자신의 집에 갈 것이다.
Ah, I can go?
아, 갈 수 있나요?
You should've said so earlier.
더 일찍 그렇게 말했어야 했는데.
I'm clocking out on time.
나는 정시에 퇴근하고 있어요.
Si Hyeong!
시형!
Don't make it obvious. Seriously, don't let it show.
그것을 명백하게 만들지 마십시오. 진심으로, 보여주지 마세요.
Alright.
괜찮은.
- Good work today. - You worked hard.
- 오늘 수고했어. - 열심히 일했어요.
- Yes, see you tomorrow. - Yes.
- 네, 내일 봐요. - 예.
That's right.
좋아요.
Jang Hui Won wouldn't have brought an umbrella.
장희원은 안 그럴거야 우산을 가져왔습니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Oh.
오.
Don't tell me you were planning to walk in the rain?
당신이 그랬다고 말하지 마세요 비를 맞으며 걸을 계획이신가요?
What could I do? I didn't have an umbrella.
내가 무엇을 할 수 있나요? 나는 우산이 없었습니다.
The chance of rain was over 70%. Did you not check the weather?
비 올 확률이 70%가 넘었습니다. 날씨를 확인하지 않았나요?
I've been too busy to check.
너무 바빠서 확인할 수가 없었습니다.
Unlike some people, every day's a battle for me.
어떤 사람들과는 달리, 나에게는 매일이 전쟁이다.
What if you, a pregnant woman, catch a cold?
임산부가 감기에 걸린다면?
Ugh, enough with the nagging.
아, 잔소리는 이제 그만.
What kind of president chases an employee after work just to nag them?
어떤 대통령이 직원을 쫓는가 퇴근하고 잔소리하려고?
So why did you come?
그럼 왜 왔나요?
Do you need something from me?
나한테 필요한 게 있나요?
It's not leftovers, and it's not from someone else. Take it.
남은 음식도 아니고, 그렇지도 않아요 다른 사람에게서. 가져가세요.
You drove me just to give me this?
나한테 이걸 주려고 운전한 거야?
'Just'? Just?
'단지'? 단지?
Do you even know what kind of handmade syrup this is?
혹시 어떤 종류인지 아시나요? 수제 시럽이요?
How would I know that?
내가 그걸 어떻게 알겠어요?
Well, this syrup...
그런데 이 시럽은...
I personally made it, paying attention to every single step.
제가 직접 만든건데, 모든 단계에 주의를 기울이는 것.
Have you ever made jujube syrup?
대추 시럽을 만들어 본 적이 있나요?
You have to scrub it clean with baking soda,
베이킹소다로 깨끗이 닦아주셔야 해요
remove the stems and seeds, and carefully prepare each piece of fruit.
줄기와 씨를 제거하고, 그리고 과일 하나하나를 조심스럽게 준비하세요.
It takes a lot of care to grind it finely
곱게 갈기 위해서는 세심한 주의가 필요합니다
and simmer it over low heat.
그리고 약한 불로 끓입니다.
Are you angry because it was hard to make?
만들기 힘들어서 화가 났나요?
Do you know how many batches failed just to make this one bottle?
배치가 몇 개인지 아시나요? 이 한 병을 만드는 데 실패했나요?
- And you call it 'just'? - So why bother?
- 그런데 그걸 '그냥'이라고 부르나요? - 그럼 왜 귀찮게 하는 거죠?
No one asked you, but why?
아무도 물어보지 않았는데 왜요?
Well, obviously...
음, 분명히...
Because you are a top-tier employee.
왜냐하면 당신은 최고 직급의 직원이기 때문입니다.
- What? - They say you're outstanding.
- 무엇? - 당신이 훌륭하다고 하던데.
Your problem-solving skills are excellent.
당신의 문제 해결 능력은 훌륭합니다.
We have so much to tackle together.
우리는 함께 해결해야 할 일이 너무 많습니다.
I can't just watch you wear yourself out.
당신이 지쳐가는 걸 보고만 있을 수는 없어요.
So I brought something good for morning sickness,
그래서 뭔가를 가져왔어 입덧에 좋고,
yet you are drinking cheap stuff from another man.
그런데 넌 싸구려 술을 마시고 있구나 다른 남자에게서.
How could I not get angry?
어떻게 화를 내지 않을 수 있겠습니까?
What?
무엇?
Nothing.
아무것도 아님.
[Mom]
[엄마]
Hold on, I need to take this call.
잠깐만요, 이 전화를 받아야 해요.
Yes.
예.
- Yes. - Son?
- 예. - 아들?
That high-pitched voice means another blind date, right?
그 높은 목소리의 뜻은 또 소개팅이죠?
If that's what this is about, I don't need...
그런거라면 필요없어...
Why? Are you seeing someone?
왜요? 만나는 사람 있어요?
Don't tell me that's why you asked for the jujube syrup recipe back then?
나한테 말하지 마세요, 그래서 당신이 요청한 거예요 그때 대추시럽 레시피는요?
- Mom. - Well, if not, forget it.
- 엄마. - 그렇지 않다면 잊어버리세요.
I met someone really nice when I went for a massage.
정말 좋은 사람을 만났어요 마사지 받으러 갔을 때
They say one detail speaks volumes.
그들은 하나의 세부 사항이 많은 것을 말해준다고 말합니다.
She grew up very upright under a single father.
그녀는 아주 꼿꼿하게 자랐어요 홀아버지 밑에서.
Mom, you don't have prejudice against things like that, do you?
엄마, 편견은 없어요 그런 것에 반대하는 거죠, 그렇죠?
I'm saying that because not many were raised properly in those circumstances.
많지 않으니까 그런 말을 하는 거야 그런 상황에서 제대로 자랐어요.
Mom, you shouldn't say that.
엄마, 그런 말씀하시면 안 돼요.
Then what about Se Hyeon?
그럼 세현은요?
Se Hyeon turned out fine
세현이 잘생겼다
because you played the role of a father since her childhood.
당신이 그 역할을 맡았으니까요 어린 시절부터 아버지였습니다.
No.
아니요.
She would've grown up better if it weren't for me.
그 사람은 더 잘 자랐을 텐데 내가 아니었다면.
Without pain, just surrounded by love.
고통 없이, 단지 사랑에 둘러싸여 있을 뿐입니다.
[Mourn]
[애도]
Uncle, why are you crying?
삼촌, 왜 울어요?
Se Hyeon, you are here.
세현아, 너 왔구나.
I'm not crying.
나는 울고 있지 않습니다.
- I never cry. - Where's Dad?
- 난 절대 울지 않아요. - 아빠는 어디 계시나요?
Why is Dad over there?
아빠는 왜 거기 있어?
He is...
그는 ...
I'm sorry.
미안해요.
I'm outside now. Let's talk later.
나는 지금 밖에 있다. 나중에 얘기하자.
Du Jun.
두준
Food delivery's here.
음식 배달이 왔습니다.
What's the occasion?
어떤 행사인가요?
No matter how busy you are, you have to eat.
아무리 바빠도 밥은 먹어야 한다.
You look thinner every time I see you.
볼 때마다 더 날씬해 보여요.
Cut down on the coffee too.
커피도 줄이세요.
And stretch your neck and shoulders more often.
그리고 목을 펴세요. 그리고 어깨가 더 자주.
Okay.
좋아요.
Hard to tell who's the mom and who's the daughter.
엄마가 누구인지 말하기가 어렵습니다. 그리고 딸은 누구지?
Dad would've really liked
아빠가 정말 좋아하셨을 거에요
seeing us like this, right?
우리 이렇게 보는 거 맞죠?
Do you miss Dad?
아빠가 그리워요?
Not really.
설마.
Uncle's like a dad to me anyway.
어쨌든 삼촌은 나에게 아빠 같은 존재다.
But he isn't your dad.
하지만 그 사람은 네 아빠가 아니야.
Your dad was so good to you.
네 아버지는 너에게 정말 잘해주셨어.
Well, I was too young back then.
글쎄요, 그땐 제가 너무 어렸거든요.
If not for that incident, your dad would've been way better than your uncle.
그 사건이 아니었다면 네 아버지는 네 삼촌보다 훨씬 나았을 거야.
Don't say things that would hurt Dad.
아빠에게 상처가 될 말은 하지 마세요.
You startled me.
당신은 나를 놀라게 했습니다.
Alright, let's eat quickly. You must be hungry, hurry.
알았어, 빨리 먹자. 배가 고프겠군요. 서둘러요.
Alright.
괜찮은.
Sorry, the call took longer than expected.
죄송합니다. 통화가 예상보다 오래 걸렸습니다.
What's wrong? Are you sick?
무슨 일이야? 당신은 아픈가요?
I'm okay.
난 괜찮아.
I got caught in the rain earlier, so I feel off.
아까 비를 맞았는데, 그래서 기분이 나빠요.
You have a fever.
열이 나네요.
Let's go to the hospital right now.
지금 당장 병원으로 가보자.
No.
아니요.
I'll be fine if I just go home and rest.
그냥 집에 가서 쉬면 괜찮을 것 같아요.
And what if your fever gets worse?
그리고 열이 더 심해지면 어쩌지?
Don't you know pregnant women can't take medicine casually?
임산부는 모르시나요? 함부로 약을 먹을 수 없나요?
I'm really fine.
난 정말 괜찮아요.
I have to go to work tomorrow. I just want to go home and rest.
나는 내일 출근해야 해요. 그냥 집에 가서 쉬고 싶어요.
I'm really okay.
난 정말 괜찮아요.
Oh, that's cold.
아, 추워요.
You need to cool down, stay still.
몸을 식히고 가만히 있어야 합니다.
My house is still messy too.
우리 집도 여전히 지저분해요.
Is that what you're worried about now?
지금 그게 걱정되는 거야?
I'll enjoy the homemade syrup.
집에서 만든 시럽을 즐겨보겠습니다.
No one's ever cared for me when I was sick like this before.
아무도 나를 돌봐주지 않았어 예전에 이렇게 아팠을 때.
To be honest, I'm touched.
솔직히 말해서 감동받았어요.
At least you know that now.
적어도 당신은 지금 그것을 알고 있습니다.
Wait a moment.
잠시만 기다려주세요.
Your fever isn't breaking.
당신의 열은 깨지지 않습니다.
Why don't you tell the company and take some rest?
회사에 말하지 그래? 그리고 좀 쉬어?
I told you. I have too much on my plate.
내가 말했잖아. 내 접시에 너무 많은 것이 있습니다.
If you're worried about your career,
진로 때문에 고민이시라면
I told you before, I can help you enough.
아까 말했잖아, 내가 충분히 도와줄 수 있다고.
Whether I finish it or hand it over,
내가 끝내든, 넘겨주든,
I want to decide my own ending.
결말은 내가 결정하고 싶다.
I gave up my lifelong dream with my own hands.
평생의 꿈을 포기했어요 내 손으로.
If I don't work now, I feel like I'll actually die.
지금 일을 안 하면 진짜 죽을 것 같아요.
Please stop telling me to rest.
제발 쉬라고 하지 마세요.
I understand.
이해합니다.
I know you're concerned about the baby,
당신이 아기를 걱정하고 있다는 걸 알아요
but please don't be so nice to me.
하지만 나에게 너무 친절하게 대하지 마세요.
I don't want to get the wrong idea.
나는 잘못된 생각을 갖고 싶지 않습니다.
[A family photo with my loving husband and our precious]
[사랑하는 남편과 함께한 가족사진] 그리고 우리의 소중한]
Don't let go.
놓지 마십시오.
Don't give up, please.
포기하지 마세요.
[Mom]
[엄마]
Ah, what a relief.
아, 정말 다행이네요.
Come to think of it, I didn't even hear him leave yesterday.
생각해보면 난 안 그랬어 심지어 어제 그가 떠나는 소리도 들었어.
I'll enjoy the homemade syrup.
집에서 만든 시럽을 맛있게 드겠습니다.
No one's ever cared for me when I was sick like this before.
아무도 나를 돌봐주지 않았어요 예전에 이렇게 아팠을 때.
To be honest, I'm touched.
솔직히 말해서 감동받았어요.
Oh.
오.
I know you're concerned about the baby,
당신이 아기를 걱정하고 있다는 걸 알아요
but please don't be so nice to me.
하지만 나에게 너무 친절하게 대하지 마세요.
I don't want to get the wrong idea.
나는 잘못된 생각을 갖고 싶지 않습니다.
Oh, my.
아, 이런.
Ah, this is embarrassing.
아, 이거 부끄럽다.
[President Kang Du Jun]
[강두준 회장]
- Yes? - How are you feeling?
- 응? - 기분이 어떠세요?
Perfectly fine. Fever's gone too.
완벽하게 괜찮습니다. 발열도 사라졌습니다.
You must've had a hard time because of me yesterday.
힘들었겠구나 어제 나 때문에.
That's good to hear.
좋은 소식이네요.
Are you ready for work?
일할 준비가 되셨나요?
Still getting ready, but why...
아직 준비 중인데 왜...
Let's go on a field trip together today.
오늘은 함께 현장 학습을 떠나자.
I'm right outside your place, so get ready and come out.
나는 당신 집 바로 밖에 있어요. 그러니 준비하고 나오세요.
Outside my place?
내 집 밖에요?
What do I do?
어떻게 해야 하나요?
Ah, seriously.
아, 정말요.
Jeez.
이런.
What am I supposed to do if he contacts me out of the blue like this?
그 사람이라면 나는 어떻게 해야 할까? 갑자기 나한테 이렇게 연락해?
But is this a date or work?
그런데 이게 데이트야, 일이야?
He said it was a field trip earlier.
아까 현장 학습이었다고 하더군요.
Ah, I don't know, I don't know.
아, 모르겠어요, 모르겠어요.
Is this better?
이게 더 나은가요?
This one looks a bit prettier.
이게 좀 더 예뻐 보이네요.
Those are the eyes of someone who's in love.
그것은 사랑에 빠진 사람의 눈입니다.
No, it's not!
아니요, 그렇지 않습니다!
You look cool.
당신은 멋지다.
I mean, the clothes, the clothes!
내 말은, 옷, 옷!
Judging by how dressed up you are, were you expecting a date or something?
옷을 얼마나 차려입었는지 판단해보면, 데이트 같은 걸 기대하고 있었나요?
Well, you said we should go out three times a week or so.
글쎄, 우리가 해야 한다고 했잖아 일주일에 세 번 정도 외출하세요.
Let's just go.
그냥 가자.
Where are we going?
우리는 어디로 가는 걸까요?
I'm saying this just in case you might misunderstand.
만약을 대비해 이렇게 말하는 거야 당신은 오해할 수도 있습니다.
About what I said, that I was touched or no one ever cared...
내가 한 말에 감동받았어 아니면 아무도 신경쓰지 않던가...
You're not actually believing that, right?
당신은 실제로 그것을 믿지 않는 거죠, 그렇죠?
Weren't you really touched?
정말 감동받지 않았나요?
I knew this would happen.
나는 이런 일이 일어날 것이라는 것을 알았습니다.
Do you really think I meant it?
내가 진심으로 그랬다고 생각해요?
Even back in school, during every break,
학교에서도 쉬는시간마다
so many guys would come bearing gifts.
정말 많은 남자들이 선물을 들고 올 거예요.
But I didn't ask.
하지만 나는 묻지 않았습니다.
Anyway, yesterday I had a fever
아무튼 어제는 열이 났어요
and said some nonsense, just so you know.
말도 안되는 말을 했어요.
You're the one who contacted me?
나한테 연락한 사람이 당신이에요?
Yes, I contacted you through my secretary.
네, 제 비서를 통해 연락했어요.
Yes.
예.
- I'm Kang Du Jun. - Yes.
- 강두준이에요. - 네.
[President Kang Du Jun]
[강두준 회장]
Oh, my. I never imagined the President would personally visit our hop farm.
아, 이런. 대통령님은 상상도 못했는데 저희 홉 농장을 직접 방문하겠습니다.
So it really is work?
그럼 정말 일인가요?
We might be working together for a long time, so I wanted to greet you personally.
우리는 오랫동안 함께 일할 수도 있고, 그래서 직접 인사드리고 싶었어요.
Ah, and this is our...
아 그리고 이건 우리...
Hello.
안녕하세요.
I'm Manager Jang Hui Won from the New Product Development Team.
저는 장희원 매니저입니다 신제품 개발팀에서.
Oh, yes.
아, 그렇죠.
I rushed out and forgot my business card.
급히 나가서 명함을 잊어버렸어요.
Oh.
오.
You must be a very capable employee.
당신은 매우 유능한 직원이어야합니다.
Thank you both for coming such a long way.
먼 길을 와주신 두 분 모두 감사드립니다.
Please feel free to look around.
편하게 둘러보시기 바랍니다.
If you have any questions, call me anytime.
궁금한 점이 있으시면 언제든지 전화주세요.
Yes.
예.
Let's go.
갑시다.
Why did you wear such uncomfortable shoes?
왜 이렇게 불편한 신발을 신었나요?
If you'd told me where we were going beforehand, that would've been nice.
우리가 어디로 가는지 말해줬더라면 미리 그랬으면 좋았을 텐데.
Well then, shall we go somewhere nice for dinner?
그럼, 가볼까? 저녁 먹기 좋은 곳?
No, thanks.
아니요, 고마워요.
What are you doing now?
뭐하세요?
Don't do that.
그러지 마세요.
- Don't do that. - Feels refreshing, right?
- 그러지 마세요. - 기분이 상쾌해지죠?
Are you trying to pick a fight?
싸움을 선택하려고 하시나요?
Huh?
뭐?
Stop it, let's stop.
그만해, 그만하자
What are you gonna do? What are you gonna do?
무엇을 할 건가요? 무엇을 할 건가요?
Feels good, right?
기분이 좋죠?
Jeez.
맙소사.
The beer pairing business targeting campers is
맥주 페어링 사업 캠핑카를 타겟으로 하는 것은
- Our Manager Jang's... - Manager Jang.
- 우리 장과장님.. - 장과장님.
- That new product set to launch next year... - The new pitch.
- 내년 출시 예정인 신제품… - 새로운 경기장.
Ah, Manager Jang is out on an assignment, huh?
아 장과장님은 나갔구나 임무 중이야, 응?
- No. - Manager Jang, just now,
- 아니. - 장과장님, 방금.
we got a call from the factory about the Try golden ratio glass...
공장에서 전화가 왔어 Try 황금비율 유리에 대해...
Manager Jang is out on an assignment, right?
장과장님은 출장중이시죠?
Exactly, yes.
그렇죠.
Manager Jang!
장 매니저님!
Ah, right. She's not here today.
아, 그렇죠. 그녀는 오늘 여기에 없습니다.
It feels kind of empty with just Manager Jang missing.
뭔가 공허한 느낌 장 매니저만 없어진 채.
Exactly.
정확히.
I never knew Manager Jang's absence would feel this big.
난 장과장을 전혀 몰랐어 부재가 이렇게 크게 느껴질 것 같아요.
Is the field trip going well?
견학은 잘 진행되고 있나요?
Should I give her a call?
그녀에게 전화를 해야 하나?
- Yes. - Then we should cover for her.
- 예. - 그럼 우리가 그 사람을 대신해야 해요.
Is this the time to wistfully stare at her empty seat and chat?
지금이 아련하게 바라볼 때인가 그녀의 빈 자리에 앉아 수다를 떨까?
Why is the team leader in such a low mood?
팀장은 왜 이렇게 기분이 좋지 않은 걸까요?
Do you want me to show you what 'really low mood' looks like?
내가 보여주기를 원하시나요? '정말 우울한 기분'은 어떤 모습인가요?
Huh? What? Do you need me for something?
뭐? 무엇? 내가 필요한 게 있나요?
Even I, the team leader, haven't had it, yet a field trip with the President?
팀장인 나조차도 그런 적이 없었는데, 아직 대통령과 견학을 가셨나요?
Does that even make sense?
그게 말이 되나요?
Did you get home safely after the team dinner?
집에 무사히 잘 도착하셨나요? 팀 저녁 식사 후에?
Team Leader Bang Soon Yi.
방순이 팀장.
Yes, thanks to you.
네, 고마워요.
But I asked you not to call me by my full name.
그런데 그러지 말라고 했어요 내 이름으로 불러주세요.
It's a bit old-fashioned.
조금 구식입니다.
My parents just made it up in a haste when life was tough.
부모님이 방금 만드셨는데 삶이 힘들 때 서둘러.
Bang Soon Yi.
방순이.
It's dainty and cute.
앙증맞고 귀엽습니다.
Pardon?
뭐라고요?
Ah.
아.
You have unique taste.
당신은 독특한 취향을 가지고 있습니다.
Come on, it's cute.
어서, 귀엽습니다.
Oh, I mean the name is cute, of course.
아, 물론 이름도 귀엽습니다.
Ah.
아.
Ah, wow, the corn is perfectly cooked.
아, 와, 옥수수가 완벽하게 익었어요.
- Oh, my. - Oh, my. Give it here.
- 아, 이런. - 아, 이런. 여기로 주세요.
Sit down, sit down.
앉아, 앉아.
Oh, it's fine.
아, 괜찮아요.
It's way too much for us to eat.
우리가 먹기에는 너무 많은 양이에요.
Go ahead, just help yourself.
계속해서 스스로 도와주세요.
Yes, thank you.
네, 감사합니다.
Want one?
하나 원하시나요?
Wow, it's been ages since I last had corn.
와, 옥수수를 먹은 지 꽤 오래 됐네요.
I'll enjoy it!
나는 그것을 즐길 것이다!
Did you sprinkle sugar on this?
여기에 설탕을 뿌렸나요?
How is it this sweet?
어쩜 이렇게 달콤하지?
President, you should try one too.
대통령님도 한번 해보세요.
Delicious, right?
맛있죠?
Yes, it is delicious.
네, 맛있어요.
Oh, it's just steamed.
아, 그냥 찐 거예요.
My wife grew it herself.
아내가 직접 키웠어요.
She's so passionate about corn.
그녀는 옥수수에 대한 열정이 대단해요.
She knows how much work it takes,
그녀는 얼마나 많은 노력이 필요한지 알고 있습니다.
but she's very enthusiastic about tending the soil and watering.
하지만 그 사람은 정말 열정적이야 흙을 가꾸고 물을 주는 것에 대해.
I can tell just by how plump these kernels are.
얼마나 통통한지 알 수 있죠 이 커널은 다음과 같습니다.
I can really taste the care you both put into this farm.
정말 케어의 맛이 느껴지네요 너희 둘 다 이 농장에 투자했어.
It's truly delicious.
정말 맛있어요.
The best?
최고?
I'll send the email as soon as I confirm it.
확인되는 대로 이메일을 보내드리겠습니다.
Yes, I'll be in touch.
네, 연락할게요.
Okay.
좋아요.
That car from before.
아까 그 차.
This is the President's designated spot.
이곳은 대통령이 지정한 곳이다.
[Reserved Parking]
[예약주차장]
I'd like to see a report organized in your unique style.
정리된 보고서를 보고 싶습니다. 당신의 독특한 스타일로.
It can be done by the end of this week, right?
할 수 있어요 이번주말쯤이겠죠?
Why are you interfering with her sleeping schedule?
왜 방해하는 거야? 그녀의 수면 일정은?
From now on, please refrain from calling Ms. Jang Hui Won
이제부터 자제해주세요 장희원씨한테 전화해서
for personal matters after 7 PM.
개인사정으로 오후 7시 이후에는
Well.
잘.
[Reserved Parking]
[예약주차장]
Let's go home!
집에 가자!
- Time to go! - Let's go.
- 이제 갈 시간이에요! - 갑시다.
Oh, Assistant Manager Cha.
아, 차 대리님.
- Hello. - Yes, hello.
- 안녕하세요. - 네, 안녕하세요.
Are you heading home now?
지금 집으로 가는 중인가요?
You came for Manager Jang, huh?
장과장님 찾으러 오셨죠?
Yes, I came to see if we could leave together,
응, 보러 왔어 우리가 함께 떠날 수 있다면,
but I don't see her.
하지만 나는 그녀를 볼 수 없습니다.
Manager Jang went on a field trip with the President.
장 매니저는 계속해서 대통령과의 견학.
- I guess you didn't hear. - A field trip?
- 못 들으셨나 보군요. - 견학?
Yes, and just the two of them.
네, 그리고 둘만요.
- Just the two of them? - Yes.
- 둘만요? - 예.
They said they're visiting a hop farm for research.
방문한다고 하더군요 연구용 홉 농장.
I knew Manager Jang was ambitious, but I didn't realize she was this driven.
장과장님이 야망이 있으신 건 알았지만, 하지만 나는 그녀가 이렇게 추진력이 있다는 것을 몰랐습니다.
I'd feel uncomfortable being alone with the President.
불편할 것 같아요 대통령과 단둘이 있는 것.
I bet the President feels uncomfortable being alone with Manager Nah too.
대통령이 불편할 것 같아요 나 감독님과 단둘이 있는 것도.
- Assistant Manager Choi. - Since they went out,
- 최 대리. - 그들이 나갔기 때문에,
will they clock out from there together?
그들은 거기에서 함께 시계를 볼 것인가?
Well, they'll probably leave straight from there.
글쎄요, 아마 그럴 거예요. 거기서 바로 떠나세요.
They say the water and scenery are beautiful there.
물이라고 하더군요 그리고 그곳의 풍경은 아름답습니다.
It feels more like a getaway than work.
일이라기보다는 휴양지 같은 느낌이 듭니다.
Come on, don't you all know Manager Jang?
자, 장과장님을 다들 아시죠?
She'll work diligently and return tomorrow with an amazing idea.
그녀는 열심히 일하고 돌아올 것이다 내일 놀라운 아이디어로.
- Right! - Probably not?
- 오른쪽! - 아마 아닐 거예요?
Admit it, Manager Jang is passionate!
인정하세요, 장과장님은 열정이 많으십니다!
Then let's passionately clock out for the day!
그럼 열정적으로 오늘은 퇴근하세요!
We should go.
우리는 가야 해요.
- Yes. - Come on in.
- 예. - 들어오세요.
Goodbye.
안녕.
See you.
또 봐요.
The farm is larger than I expected with numerous hop plants,
농장이 생각보다 넓네요 수많은 홉 식물로
so I think future collaboration would be beneficial.
그래서 나는 미래의 협력을 생각한다 유익할 것입니다.
Sign a contract with us.
우리와 계약을 체결하세요.
We'll help you earn five times your current annual revenue.
5배 수익을 도와드리겠습니다 귀하의 현재 연간 수익.
What? Five times?
무엇? 다섯 번?
I know you already supply domestic hops to several other breweries.
이미 국산 홉을 공급하고 있는 것으로 알고 있습니다. 다른 여러 양조장에.
We won't interfere with that.
우리는 그것에 간섭하지 않을 것입니다.
However, to meet our supply demands,
그러나 우리의 공급 수요를 충족시키기 위해
you'll need to triple your current hop production.
현재 전류를 3배로 늘려야 합니다 홉 생산.
Is that feasible?
그게 가능할까요?
We have to make it happen, of course.
물론 우리는 그것을 실현해야 합니다.
Oh dear, honey.
아, 얘야.
Absolutely. We'll meet the demand even if we have to hire more help.
전적으로. 우리는 수요를 충족시킬 것입니다 더 많은 도움을 고용해야 하더라도.
- Oh, wow. - Thank you.
- 아, 와. - 감사합니다.
You'll be swamped starting tomorrow. Wow.
내일부터 당신은 푹 빠질 것입니다. 우와.
You've worked hard.
당신은 열심히 일했습니다.
You'll get busy soon!
곧 바빠질 거예요!
Don't they look perfect together?
서로 완벽해 보이지 않나요?
What is marriage, really?
결혼이란 과연 무엇인가?
How can two people from different lives
어떻게 서로 다른 삶을 살아온 두 사람이
cherish each other like their own selves
서로를 자기 자신처럼 소중히 여기고
for so long like that?
그렇게 오랫동안?
Someone said people marry
누군가 말했지, 사람은 결혼한다고
because they desperately need someone on their side.
왜냐면 그들은 필사적으로 옆에 누군가가 필요해요.
Marriage
결혼
completes the insecure part of themselves.
자신의 불안한 부분을 완성합니다.
My side...
내 편...
You should've been on my side.
당신은 내 편이어야 했어요.
Even if everyone else turns their backs,
모두가 등을 돌리더라도
you should have been with me!
당신은 나와 함께 있었어야 했어요!
And if the person you trusted to be on your side betrays you,
그리고 당신이 믿었던 사람이 있다면 네 편이 되는 것은 너를 배신하는 일이다.
doesn't it hurt even more?
더 아프지 않아?
Even if you start out inseparable,
뗄래야 뗄 수 없는 시작을 하더라도
eventually you may end up as enemies or strangers.
결국 당신은 끝날 수 있습니다 적 또는 낯선 사람으로.
Maybe it's better not to start at all.
어쩌면 전혀 시작하지 않는 것이 더 나을 수도 있습니다.
Is it
그렇습니까?
because of your mother?
엄마 때문에?
[Mom: My life got completely ruined because of you.]
[엄마: 내 인생이 완전해졌어. 너 때문에 망했어.]
My life got completely ruined because of you.
너 때문에 내 인생이 완전히 망가졌어.
You should never have been born.
당신은 태어나지 말았어야 했어요.
You don't need to react to words meant to hurt you.
반응할 필요는 없어 당신에게 상처를 주려는 말.
It's not your fault. Far from it.
그것은 당신의 잘못이 아닙니다. 그것과는 거리가 멀다.
Did you happen to see my text?
혹시 내 문자 봤어?
I didn't mean to see it, sorry.
보려고 한 건 아니었는데, 미안해요.
But your life is too precious to be swayed by such words.
하지만 네 목숨은 너무 소중해 그런 말에 흔들리게 된다.
Don't pretend to understand me.
나를 이해하는 척하지 마십시오.
You grew up sheltered, so you might not realize how hard that is,
당신은 보호받는 곳에서 자랐기 때문에 그렇지 않을 수도 있습니다. 그게 얼마나 힘든 일인지 깨닫고,
but for some, it's a lifelong struggle.
그러나 일부에게는 평생의 투쟁입니다.
Wait, I...
잠깐, 난...
Please drop me off here.
저를 여기에서 내려주세요.
Thank you for the ride.
태워주셔서 감사합니다.
I'll should go.
나는 가야만 한다.
Are you really leaving like this?
정말 이대로 떠나는 거야?
Thank you for your hard work today.
오늘 당신의 노고에 감사드립니다.
I'll send you the hop farm proposal as soon as it's finalized.
홉팜 제안서 보내드릴게요 확정되자마자.
No...
아니...
You shouldn't take it out on someone who took your side.
꺼내시면 안됩니다 당신 편을 들어준 누군가에게.
How pathetic. Truly pathetic, Jang Hui Won.
얼마나 한심한가. 정말 한심하다, 장희원.
Huh?
뭐?
Min Uk.
민욱.
Where have you been?
어디 있었어?
Were you with that person?
그 사람이랑 같이 있었어?
- Huh? - The baby's father.
- 뭐? - 아기의 아버지.
Is it President Kang Du Jun?
강두준 회장님이신가요?
I see.
알겠어요.
I'm sorry, I was going to tell you...
미안해요, 말하려고 했는데...
What about the baby?
아기는 어떻습니까?
Have you decided?
결정하셨나요?
I'm going to keep it.
나는 그것을 지킬 것이다.
- Hui Won. - I'm not giving up my dream.
- 희원. - 나는 꿈을 포기하지 않는다.
I'm just postponing it.
그냥 미루고 있는 중이에요.
After giving birth, I'll thrive and do everything I want.
출산하고 나면 더 잘 자라겠네요 그리고 내가 원하는 건 다 해주세요.
But you said you didn't want marriage.
그런데 결혼하고 싶지 않다고 하더군요.
And now you plan to keep it and raise it alone?
그리고 이제 당신은 그것을 유지할 계획입니다 혼자서 키울까?
I can do it. I can.
나는 할 수 있다. 나는 할 수 있다.
While you're thinking about this,
당신이 이것에 대해 생각하고 있는 동안,
where is he, and what is he doing?
그 사람은 어디에 있고, 무엇을 하고 있나요?
Shouldn't there be some plan?
뭔가 계획이 있어야 하지 않겠습니까?
He said he would take responsibility.
책임을 지겠다고 밝혔습니다.
I refused.
나는 거절했다.
He said he'd take responsibility?
자기가 책임지겠다고 했죠?
Is he saying you should marry him or what?
그 사람이 당신이 그 사람과 결혼해야 한다고 말하는 건가요?
A chaebol heir who can do anything with money,
할 수 있는 재벌 상속인 돈이면 뭐든지 할 수 있다
can he really do that just because of a kid?
정말 그 아이 때문에 그럴 수 있는 걸까?
What if I can?
내가 할 수 있다면 어떨까요?
I don't understand why this is impossible right now.
왜 이런지 이해가 안 돼요 지금은 불가능합니다.
- President... - If something like this happened,
- 대통령님... - 이런 일이 있었다면,
wouldn't you take responsibility?
책임을 지지 않겠습니까?
I wouldn't create such an awkward situation in the first place.
나는 창조하지 않을 것이다 애초에 이런 어색한 상황이라니.
Hey.
여기요.
If you're planning to use Hui Won, stop right here.
이용하실 예정이시라면 희원아, 여기서 멈춰라.
She's not someone for people like you to toy with.
그녀는 누군가가 아니다 당신 같은 사람들이 가지고 놀 수 있도록 말이죠.
I've never thought of it that way.
나는 그런 식으로 생각한 적이 없습니다.
Do you think so too, Ms. Jang Hui Won?
장희원 선생님도 그렇게 생각하시나요?
Do you think I'm toying with you?
내가 당신을 가지고 놀고 있다고 생각하나요?
What?
무엇?
Then why not check if that's true?
그렇다면 그것이 사실인지 확인해 보는 것은 어떨까요?
See whether I'm being sincere now.
지금 내가 진심인지 확인해 보세요.
Lately, I don't know why I'm having these thoughts.
최근에는 모르겠어요 내가 왜 이런 생각을 하는지.
You'll help, right?
당신이 도와줄 거예요, 그렇죠?
Ugh, I don't know.
아, 모르겠어요.
Oh, do you want some meat, Your Highness?
아, 고기 좀 드실래요, 폐하?
I shall prepare the meat, Your Highness.
제가 고기를 준비하겠습니다, 전하.
I get angry just seeing her giggle with another guy.
보기만 해도 화가 난다 그녀가 다른 남자와 낄낄거린다.
I gave up my lifelong dream with my own hands.
평생의 꿈을 포기했어요 내 손으로.
If I don't work now, I feel like I'll actually die.
지금 일을 안 하면 진짜 죽을 것 같아요.
Please stop telling me to rest.
제발 쉬라고 하지 마세요.
When she agonizes between work and the baby, I feel sorry for her.
그녀가 일 사이에 고민할 때 그리고 아기는 안타깝습니다.
How can you only think about yourself until the very end?
어떻게 생각만 할 수 있지? 마지막까지 자신에 대해?
If I were you, I would never live like you, understand?
내가 너라면 절대 안 그럴 거야. 너처럼 살아, 알았지?
If she's crying alone,
그녀가 혼자 울고 있다면,
it bothers me a lot.
그것은 나를 많이 괴롭힌다.
I even wonder why I'm talking about this right now.
내가 왜 그랬는지조차 궁금해 지금 이 얘기를 하는 중이에요.
It's just that...
단지 그게...
I want you to feel a bit at ease, at least for today.
좀 느끼해졌으면 좋겠어 적어도 오늘만큼은 안심하세요.
Does this mean
이것이 의미하는 바는 무엇입니까?
I'm falling for you?
내가 당신에게 반하고 있다고요?
[Epilogue]
[에필로그]
- Daddy.
- 아빠.
Daddy, don't go.
아빠, 가지 마세요.
Don't go.
가지 마세요.
Daddy.
아빠.
Don't leave Mom behind.
엄마를 뒤에 남겨두지 마세요.
It isn't easy for you either.
그것은 당신에게도 쉽지 않습니다.
Daddy.
아빠.
I'm not leaving.
나는 떠나지 않을 것이다.
Never.
절대.
Are you avoiding me?
나를 피하고 있나요?
It seems like you've been burdened because of my confession.
부담이 되셨을 것 같은데요 내 고백 때문에.
Don't avoid me.
나를 피하지 마십시오.
You like your friend, huh?
너 친구 좋아하는구나, 응?
Why are you just watching and doing nothing?
왜 아무것도 하지 않고 지켜보기만 합니까?
How truly vulgar.
정말 저속합니다.
The liquor model got a DUI? Isn't that insane?
주류 모델이 음주운전을 했다고요? 그거 미친거 아냐?
If we can't fix this,
우리가 이 문제를 해결할 수 없다면,
it'll be hard to keep our footing.
우리의 발판을 유지하기가 어려울 것입니다.
Then we must find
그럼 우리는 찾아야 해
a new model to revitalize our image.
우리의 이미지를 되살리기 위한 새로운 모델입니다.
Well, my colleagues.
글쎄요, 동료들.
How would they react if they found out I'm pregnant?
그들은 어떻게 반응할까요? 내가 임신한 걸 그들이 알게 된다면?
Why? Did anyone say anything to you?
왜? 누군가 당신에게 아무 말도 하지 않았나요?
- She's pregnant! - Wow! How'd she seduce him?
- 임신했어요! - 우와! 그녀는 어떻게 그를 유혹했을까요?
Well, anyone can get pregnant.
뭐, 누구나 임신할 수 있어요.
What matters is whose child it is.
중요한 것은 누구의 아이인지이다.
If it gets tough this time, will you just give up again?
이번에 힘들면 또 포기할 거야?